*Don't you even think about it!
你想都别想!
Back it up.
退后
Everybody,down!
所有人 蹲下!
I said watch it.
我说了 看那里!
I said watch it!
我说看那里!
Please,don'T.
求你 别这样!
Over the past 2 months,
在过去的两个月里
the L.A. Field office has been tracking a series of 4 bank robberies in the L.A. Metro area.
洛杉矶警方正在追查连续四起 发生在都会区的银行抢劫案
It's one individual wearing a black ski mask.
是一个戴着黑色滑雪面具的人
He's highly skilled.
他很有技巧
It's his unique M.O.
正是他独特的M.O.(惯用手法)
That put him squarely in our court.
把他送到我们的手中
This happened 2 days ago.
这是两天前的
He's making them undress?
他让他们都脱光?
He takes their clothes and locks them in the vault,
他脱下他们的衣服 并锁在保险库
then he goes for the cash.
然后就去拿现金
Smart.
很狡猾
Nobody's going to run after him buck-naked.
没有人会光着身子逃跑的
It's also a psychological advantage.
这也是一种心理上的优势
Make the captives feel exposed,intimidated,
让俘虏觉得被暴露 被羞辱
and much less likely to fight back.
不太可能反抗
That,and the mac-10 he's waving around.
他手上挥着的是MAC-10枪
Boy's got a lot of firepower.
这小子有很足的火力阿
But why is this case for us?
为什么我们负责这个案子?
Because in the last robbery,2 things changed.
因为在上次抢劫中 两件事发生了变化
1,he beat the security guard nearly senseless,
第一 他把保安打得几乎不省人事
and 2,after he made everyone undress,
第二 在大家脱完衣服后
he forced 2 pairs of victims together at gunpoint,
他拿枪逼着两对受害者到一起
then he made them simulate sex with each other.
然后让他们互相模拟做爱
Whoa.
哇噢
It's remarkable.
很可观阿
By utilizing your practical M.O.
通过利用实用的M.O.(惯用手法)
The subject has stumbled on to a psychological signature.
他已无意中形成心理上的特征
It's fascinating.
很迷人
He's a sex offender now.
他现在是性侵犯者
Fueled by violent rage.
被暴怒所激起
Only our unsub doesn't know it yet.
只有我们的嫌犯还不知道这点
If he did,he wouldn't be robbing banks anymore.
要是他知道了 便不会再抢劫银行
So,he's a violent sex offender in denial.
所以 他是个暴力性侵犯者 即使他否认
And a sexual predator.
还有性掠夺者
Who's just escalated his crimes.
他已使罪行升级
He's a serial killer in the making.
他正一步步变成连环杀手
Hey,what are you doing here?
嘿 你来这里干什么?
Your cell phone kept going straight to voicemail.
你的手机一直转到语音信箱
Yeah,no,I was in a meeting.
是的 我刚刚在开会
Is everything all right?
没什么事吧?
Going out of town?
你要出城?
Yeah,we're going to L.A.
恩 我们要去洛杉矶
I was going to call you from the car.
我本想上车再打给你
What is it?
怎么了?
You really don't know why I'm here?
你真的不知道我为什么来?
Honey,I'm sorry,
亲爱的 对不起
we're running late.
我们要迟到了
I just got back from the hospital.
我刚从医院回来
Jack?
Jack?
Oh,my god,the tests.
我的天 那些测试
What happened?
发生了什么?
He's got a condition.
他生病了
It's treatable and he's going to be ok.
可以治疗 他会没事的
Honey,I'm sorry.
亲爱的 对不起
How was he?
他怎么样?
Scared.
害怕极了
You know,they put those electrodes all over him
你知道 全身都插着电极
and he was wondering where his daddy was.
也不知道他的父亲在哪里
-Babe,you promised you'd be there. -I know.
- 宝贝 你答应过会在那的 - 我知道
I'm sorry.
对不起
Where is he now?
他现在在哪?
At home with my mom
和我妈在家里
I didn't want him here while we were talking.
我们谈话的时候 我不希望他在场
Look,I know this job is important to you,
听着 我知道这个工作对你很重要
but we're important,too.
但我们也同样重要
You don't have to tell me that.
你不必说这些
I don't want you to wake up some day in some random city
我不希望有天你在某个城市醒来
and realize that you don't know your own son.
发现你都不认识自己的儿子
They can go without me.
没有我 他们也可以去
No,they can'T.
不 他们不行
It's ok.
没关系
Go.
去吧
We'll talk about it when you get home.
你回家后我们再谈
I'm so sorry.
我很抱歉
sorry
对不起
"Man is least himself when he talks in his own person.
"当人以自己身份说话的时候 便越不是自己"
Give him a mask and he will tell you the truth."
"给他一个面具 他便会告诉你事实"
Oscar wilde.
Oscar Wilde
"Stripping bandiT."
"脱衣抢匪"
That's terrible.That makes it sound like the bandit's doing the stripping.
真恶心 听起来就像是 抢匪跳脱衣舞似的
What would you call him?
你们会怎么叫他?
Pervert.
性变态
Scumbag.
卑鄙小人
-I'd call him an ass -hey,focus,please.
- 我叫他蠢蛋 - 嘿 集中注意
We have the details of the 4 bank robberies to learn before we get to los angeles.
在到洛杉矶之前 我们得先看看 四起银行抢劫案的详细资料
At this point is he more a bank robber or a sex offender?
此时此刻 他算是银行劫匪 还是性侵犯者?
Seriously.What's he going to do next,rob a bank or rape somebody?
说正经的 他下一步会做什么? 抢劫银行还是强奸某人?
I'd say we need to know more about
我必须说 我们得知道更多关于...
how he robs the banks and who he chooses to victimize.
他如何抢劫银行和选择谁做受害者
Why these banks and why these victims?
为什么是这些银行 这些受害者?
Pairing these specific people together is a fantasy.
将这些特定人们配对 是一种荒谬的想法
If we can figure out the nature of that fantasy,
如果我们能找出这种幻想的本质
we may be able to predict his targets.
也许就能预测出他的目标
Hmm.
嗯
In the last robbery I don't see any photos of what he made the victims actually do.
在上次抢劫中 没有看见任何 他让受害者做事的照片
There is a problem with this surveillance system.
监视系统有问题
We're working on it.
我们正在调查
We should hit the ground running.How should we break it down?
我们得马上开始行动 怎么分配任务?
There's got to be a pattern to the banks.
这些银行一定有分布图
We should run a geographical profile.
我们需要建个地理方位图
It's yours.
你负责
And for the sexual aspects,
关于性的方面
we need to look at the specific victimology.
我们得研究特定的受害者
You and I can go with the victim reports,
你和我调查受害者报告
see whatever surveillance footage they got.
看看监视录像拍到了什么
We'll need the unsub himself.
我们需要了解嫌犯自己
We'll need his perspective.
需要从他的角度出发
Crime scene.
犯罪现场
The suspect entered around 2:00 P.M.
疑犯在下午2点左右进去
And a witness said he saw a man on a motorcycle
有目击证人看到一名骑摩托车
with a backpack speed by a few minutes after the robbery.
背登山包的人 在抢劫后几分钟离开
Freeway's just a few blocks that way,right?
高速公路就在几个街区外 对吧?
Actually,we're in a half-mile of 3 freeways.
事实上 半英里内就有三条高速公路
This is a perfect location.
真是完美的作案地点
If he's on a bike,he's got no trouble getting out of here.
他骑摩托车 就不难离开这里
Well,first he's got to get to his bike.
首先 他先得上他的车才行
Where's it parked?
它停在哪里?
-Not hidden anywhere. -No.
- 哪里都可能 - 不
No. No.A guy this good wouldn't risk his bike not being near when he comes out.
不 这么狡猾的人不会冒险 去把车停在比较远的地方
He'd park illegally.
他可能非法停车
Probably not in the parking lot,
也许不在停车场
but further down the block,maybe,
也许在街区那边
or right across the street here.
或者就是街对面
We need to know if any of these places have security cameras that might have caught the bike.
我们得知道这些地方 有没有监视摄像头拍到摩托车
Ready?
准备好了吗?
Let's go rob a bank.
咱们去"抢"银行了
Basically,
基本上
we assume the suspects will hunt close to where they live,
我们假设嫌犯会攻击 离他住所近的地方
but far enough to remain anonymous.
但也同时有一段距离 可以让他不被注意
Each one of these data points represents a bank that he hit,
每个数据点都代表他袭击过的银行
and this area where the lines intersect give us the best estimate of the unsub's home.
线框起来的这一区域 他的家估计就在里面
So,how many does that narrow it down to?
那缩小范围到多少人?
Uh,couple hundred thousand.
大概几十万吧
Oh.
噢
Witness statements.
证人口供
Not planning on seeing any of the sights this afternoon,were you?
你下午不打算去看这里的景点?
I've already seen the hollywood sign,
我已经看过了好莱坞标志
been to the getty center,
也去过Getty艺术中心
I'm not really interested in john wayne's footprints,
对于John Wayne的足印 我倒是没兴趣
so I guess that covers the sights of los angeles.
所以我想洛杉矶的景点也就这些了吧
Oh. Let me guess,new york?
让我猜猜 纽约人?
Now,what would make you say that?
你怎么会这么说?
Is this all the video equipment you've got?
你们只有这些视频设备吗?
It ain't quanico.
这里可不是Quantico (FBI的总部所在地)
I need to set up a link with our tech back there.
我要和我们的技术总部建立连接
We got another bay as crappy as this one down the hall.
在走廊那里我们还有个 同样蹩脚的隔间
You all right?
你还好吗?
I just need some popcorn.
我只想要爆米花
Have fun.
好好享受吧
So,he enters and he walks right to this spot.
他进来之后 走到了这个地方
Pulls his weapon and shoots into the ceiling right there.
拿出武器 向天花板开枪 就在那里
That gets everyone's attention,
那吸引了所有人的注意
let's them all know he's dead serious.
让他们知道他是极度危险的
Efficient.
很有效率
This is the best spot in the bank.
这里是银行里的最佳位置
I can see all the tellers,the front door,
我可以看见所有的出纳员 前门
and that's the back office over there.
还有那里的后勤办公室
So,he knew exactly where to go.
所以他确切地知道该怎么做
He had been here before.
他曾来过这里
Next.
然后呢
Next,he turns,aims the gun at the guard.
然后他转身 用枪指着保安
Don't you even think about it!
你想都别想!
Back it up.
退后
Disarms the guard and handcuffs him to the base.
让他放下武器 并把他铐在了下面
So,where's the threat?
怎么构成威胁?
The guard's disarmed and chained.
保安没有武器 也被锁了起来
How's he a threat to the unsub?
他怎么对嫌犯构成威胁?
He isn'T.
他没有
Then why did he take the time to assault?
那为什么还要花时间去攻击他呢?
He's got control,
他已经控制了局面
he's obviously got skills,
显然也很有技巧
the very thing that he doesn't have is time.
他唯一没有的就是时间
He didn't assault the guards in the previous banks,why?
之前的银行里 他没有对保安施暴 这是为什么?
What's changed? What's different about this guard?
有什么变化? 这个保安有什么不同?
Maybe this guard reminded him of somebody.
也许保安使他想起了某个人
What were the other guards in the previous robberies wearing?
之前的抢劫中 保安穿什么?
Uniforms?
制服?
Black suits.
黑色套装
That's it.
就是这个
That's all.
就是这些
Our boy's efficient,
我们的嫌犯很有效率
he's determined.
他下定了决心
This ain't his first baby.
这不是他第一次作案
He's got his trade down cold.
他心狠手辣
Something about a guy in uniform triggers an emotional response.
身穿制服的保安触及到他的内心
Army?
军队?
Army,you're conditioned to work with people.
在军队里 你要和别人一起工作
This guy,he don't trust anybody.
这个人 他不相信任何人
Prison.
监狱
Best trade school in the country.
全国最好的技校
I got access to 4 bank robberies with security footage.
我拿到四起银行抢劫案的监控录像
What do I get to do with them?
该怎么处理这些?
You know your digital perspective whatever software?
你知道那个叫什么的 数字透视软件来着?
Digital perspective analysis rendering?
数字透视分析图?
Yeah.
就是了
Honey,not only do I know it,I helped develop it.
亲爱的 我不但知道 我还参与了它的开发
Good,'cause I want every physical dimension of the unsub:
好的 我要知道 关于嫌疑犯的一切体貌特征
Height,waist size,inseam,everything that you can give me.
身高 腰围 腿长 你能查到的一切
Honey,if he opens his mouth,
亲爱的 如果他张开嘴
I'll give you the length of his teeth.
我还会给你他牙齿的长度
Just keep it clean and don't call me honey.
查查清楚 还有别叫我亲爱的
See anything interesting?
有没有看到什么有趣的?
Maybe.
也许
He took his time,
他不紧不慢
he looked at me,
他看着我
then he pointed his gun at me.
然后拿枪指着我
And you were all naked at this point?
那时你没穿衣服?
Yes.
是的
Bank manager's wife.
银行经理的妻子
She stopped by to pick him up.
顺路过来接他
They were going to celebrate their son's 16th birthday.
他们原本打算 帮他们儿子过16岁生日
The son was with them?
他儿子和他们在一起?
Daughter,too.
还有女儿
He knows the kids are theirs?
他知道孩子是他们的吗?
Well,witnesses said he checked their wallets first.
证人说 他事先检查过他们的钱包
He would have seen their names.
可能看见过他们名字
So,of all 13 people,
一共13个人
he puts together woman in her 60's,guy in his 30's,
他选出一个60多岁的女人 一个30多岁的男人
married couple in front of their kids.
还有一对孩子也在场的夫妇
Why?
为什么?
Maybe they were the most inappropriate couples he could think of.
也许这是他能想到的 最不合适的搭配
He's sadistic.
他残酷成性
Would explains why he brings them herE.
这解释了为何他把他们带到这里
He could have taken them behind the teller windows,
他可以带他们去出纳窗口后面
he could have taken them back into the vault,
或是保险库里面
but he chooses here.
但是他选择了这里
It's the most exposed place in the bank.
银行里最显眼的位置
Like a stage.
就像一个舞台
Like,it was as important for them to see what was going on as it was for him.
就像对他们来说 看着发生的事情 和对他来说是一样重要
Public humiliation.
当众羞辱
I said,watch it!
我说看着那里!
Robbery wasn't about the money;
抢劫的目的不是为了钱
it was about getting off on what he made these people do on this spot.
而是关于他让别人在大庭广众做的事情
Forcing others to squirm and watch.
使得其他人局促不安 还要观看
We got to know what exactly they were forced to do.
我们得知道他到底让他们做了什么
We need to see the fantasy.
我们要看看他的幻想
Did you ever get a hold of the security videos?
你有没有监视录像带?
Yes,but they were mostly erased.
是的 但大多数都被擦除了
That's henderson,the bank manager.
那是Henderson 银行经理
Said he was so flustered after what he had been through,
他说在经历这一切之后 他非常紧张慌乱
that when he was gathering the tapes for us,
以至于在为我们收集录像带时
he hit the wrong buttons and erased part of them.
按错了键 抹掉了其中一部分
You believe him?
你相信他?
No. I told him I thought he was embarrassed
不 我告诉他 我觉得他是因为
about the tapes getting out and he erased them on purpose.
录像带曝光使自己难堪了 才故意抹掉那部分的
He denied it.
可他否认了
You rule out the possibility he was in on it?
你就排除了他与之有牵连的可能?
Why would he be involved in a robbery when he had to go through something like that?
如果他与抢劫有牵连 为什么会遭到这种对待?
Well,maybe he didn't know what was going to happen.
也许他不知道接着会发生什么
Maybe he was betrayed by the unsub.
也许那嫌犯背叛了他
Or perhaps he was coerced.
也有可能他是被强迫的
There's been many documented cases of robbers
许多记录在案的抢劫事件中
forcing bank managers to assist them with their crimes.
劫匪强迫银行经理 协助他们进行犯罪
Yeah,none of that is consistent with the M.O.'S of the other robberies.
可现在没有哪一次 与其他抢劫的M.O.(惯用手法)一致啊
Maybe there's a reason this last one was different from the others.
最后一次抢劫不同于以往 也许是有原因的
Call from quanico on one.
Quantico总部来电话 一号线
Thanks.
谢谢
Garcia,it's hotch.
Garcia 我是Hotch
Are we ready for something completely weird?
准备好了么? 来听听很奇怪的事情
How weird are we talking,garcia?
有多奇怪 Garcia?
The security footage hotch gave me,
Hotch给我的保安监控录像
I ran it through my software 3 times...
我把它通过自制软件运行了三次...
and?
然后呢?
And there are weird height issues.
我发现了奇怪的身高问题
I.E.,The unsub in the first 3 robberies is 6 foot 1
也就是说 前三次抢劫中 嫌犯高6尺1寸
and the unsub in the last robbery,he's 5'10".
而最后一次抢劫中的嫌犯 身高5尺10寸
So what?The last robbery we're dealing with a different unsub?
怎么了? 最后一次抢劫的嫌犯不是同一人?
An unsub who is somehow able to erase tapes
这个嫌犯 不知用何种方法 能够消除
that show exactly what happened at that bank.
记录银行发生事件的录像带
An unsub who may have possibly had inside help.
这个不明人物 很有可能有内应
I think it's time we sat down with the bank manager.
我想是时候跟银行经理好好谈谈了
Look,I already told the other agent that I was nervous.
我已经告诉你们的人了 我当时很紧张
I screwed up.
搞得一团糟
I--what else do you want me to say?
我... 你们还想让我说什么?
It took you 9 minutes to call 911 after the robber left.
劫匪离开后九分钟 你才打了911
I was collecting the tapes.
我当时在整理录像带
Before you called 911?
在打911之前?
You think I had something to do with this?
你认为我与这件事有牵连?
You think I'd put my family through this?
你认为我会让我的家庭经受这一切?
No.
不
I don't think you'd put your family through letting those tapes get out either.
我认为你不会让你的家庭经受这一切 但你也不想让录像带曝光
You were the only one who had access to those tapes,mr. Henderson.
Henderson先生 你是唯一能得到这些录像带的人
Now,at best,you erased them because you were embarrassed,and at rst,
往好处想 你是因为难堪 才抹掉了一部分 而往坏处想
because you had something to do with the robbery.
你是因为与抢劫有牵连才抹掉的
Now,which one would you rather have us think?
你更愿意让我们往哪方面想?
You got to understand.
你们必须明白
We were raised baptists.
我们都是从小就受过洗礼的
It's hard for us to talk about this kind of thing.
谈论这样的事情 对我们来说可不容易
It's hard for all of us.
对大家都不容易
The thought about anybody seeing those tapes,
一想到有人会看到这些录像带
even the police...
即使是警方看到...
no.
也不行
I'm sorry.
对不起
I didn't think it would matter.
我当时想这也许无关紧要
I think it's pretty clear what this is about.
这一切关乎什么 现在已经很清楚了
Shame and humiliation.
羞耻 与 屈辱
Everybody,down!
都给我趴下
I said,watch it!
我说了 看那边!
Watch it!
看那边!
there is nothing wrong with my software.
我的软件没什么问题
My software is perfect,
我的软件是完美的
isn't it?
难道不是么?
No,it isn'T.It is.
不 不是的 哦 哦
Why must your beauty be so painful?
为什么爱美总要受罪呢?
Yeah?
什么事?
Uh,pals,
伙计
don't be ticked,
别生气
but I think I may have missed the sort of  glaringly obvious here.
不过我想 先前我大概没发现 某些很明显的东西
How would you make yourself taller without being a different person entirely or
作为同一个人 你怎么才能让自己看起来高一些?
having some sort of weird chinese surgery?
当然了 你不能去做 什么古怪的中国式手术
Heels.
鞋跟啊
Right,sunshine,but would have seen heels,
对 但我们会看到鞋跟的
unless the unsub had them hidden inside his shoe.
除非嫌犯将鞋跟藏进鞋子里
The point is,lifts.
关键就在 他穿的是内增高
Lifts.
内增高
Lifts,all hidden up inside his boot.
对 内增高 都藏进他靴子里了
With a little fancy footwork,
通过一些技巧性的操作
pun emphatically intended,
用心耍点手段
garcia here managed to dig him out.
我Garcia会设法把他找出来
Thanks,girl.
谢了 姑娘
He's trying to throw us off,
他想把我们弄晕
hide his real height.
隐藏了自己的真实身高
But why would he take the lifts out just for the last robbery?
但为什么只在最后一次 把内增高去掉?
Maybe he's getting careless.
也许 他渐渐疏忽了
Which means he's also getting more dangerous.
这也意味着 他越来越危险了
At least we know we're only dealing with one unsub.
至少我们知道 对付的嫌犯只有一个
Aah!
啊!
Based on the knowledge that spending a significant time
在狱中呆较长一段时间 会阻碍人的情感发育
in prison stunts emotional growth while increasing professional skills,
但同时 他的专业技能却有增无减 根据这一认识
we can estimate this unsub went to jail
我们可以推断 嫌犯曾在
between the ages of 18 and 22 and spent
18至22岁之间进过监狱 并在里面
between5 and 10 years inside.
呆了5至10年
That puts him at the approximate age between 23 and 35.
这意味着 他目前在23至35岁之间
This guy's much more than just a bank robber though.
这混蛋远不只是个银行劫匪
What started out as a practical M.O.,
以可操作的M.O.(惯用手法)起步
Stripping his hostages,
让人质脱衣服
triggered a deep psycho-sexual response.
触发了一种很深的性心理反应
In other words,
换句话说
when he found himself in front of a bunch of naked people under his control,
当他发现自己面前有一群人 赤身裸体 并在他掌控之下
he snapped,then he decided to manipulate them.
他会突然发作 然后决定玩弄他们
Better,or just getting worse?
情况是更好 还是更糟?
He's attacking banks earlier in the day
他袭击银行的时间越来越早
when more and more people are present.
越早 在场的人就越多
This sounds like he's sacrificing the safety of having just a few hostages to contain,
听起来像是 他放弃了 只挟持几名人质的安全做法
for the satisfaction of having more subjects to control.
只为了获得控制更多人的快感
He'll be less interested in money
他对金钱会越来越没有兴趣
and more interested in sadistically  anipulating his captives.
对丧心病狂地操纵被俘者 的兴趣却越来越强烈
In all likelihood,he's high on drugs.
他十有八九吸毒成性
It'd be wrong,however,to write this guy off as crazy.
但断然把他归为疯癫的类型 也是错误的
Bank robbing is an ambitious crime and
抢劫银行是极具挑战性的犯罪行为
it takes time and planning to pull it off.
实施起来得花费很长时间 并需要周密计划
What makes this unsub unique is his fractured psyche.
让这个嫌犯与众不同的 是他扭曲的心智
On the one hand,
一方面说来
a cold,organized bank robber.
他是冷酷的有条理银行劫匪
On the other,
而另一方面
a disorganized sexual sadist full of bottled up rage.
又是混乱无比 怒火中烧的性虐待狂
Freeze!
不许动!
Drop it!
把枪丢掉!
No.
不
Come on now,just put it down.
少废话 把枪丢掉
I got a mac-10.
我拿的可是mac-10冲锋枪
One shot.
一枪
You got one shot to kill me.
你只有一枪的机会杀了我
Even if you kill me,I'm going down shooting.
即便你射中我 倒下时我也会开枪的
The 2 parts of his psyche have just begun to bleed though,
他心智的两个对立面 刚刚开始相互渗透
and when they finally converge,
当最终融合到一点时
we're talking about a criminal
就成了我们所谓的罪犯
with the skills and efficiency of a master bank robber
劫匪技术熟练 效率很高
and the rage of a suicide bomber.
也有自杀爆炸者的满腔愤怒
He will explode.
他肯定会爆发的
Take them off.
把衣服脱了
-I said take them off. -No.
- 我说了 把衣服脱了 - 不
Take...them...off!
把... 衣服... 脱了!
Sir,bank robbery in progress.
头儿 有一起银行抢劫
Corner of washington and sepulveda.
在Washington街与Sepulveda街拐角
Kid in the back called 911 on his cell.
躲在后勤室的孩子用手机打了911
Said the suspect's started making people undress.
他说嫌犯开始让在场的人脱衣服
How far are we from the bank?
我们离那家银行有多远?
Without traffic,10 minutes.
交通顺畅的话 10分钟
Let's avoid traffic.
咱们避开车流
Do I have everybody's attention?
大家都注意了么?
How we doing?
怎么样了?
5 minutes.
还要五分钟
Make it 3.
加速 用三分钟
Please?
求你了...
Less than a mile.
还有不到一里
Just around the corner.
就在拐角
Is this your bike?
是你的车么?
Call E.M.S.!
快呼叫紧急医疗救援!
F.B.I.He took off.Where?
- FBI! - 他逃走了
I don't know.
- 往哪走了? - 不知道
Ma'am. Ma'am,can you hear me?
女士 女士 能听见我说话么?
She's unconscious.
她失去意识了
Medics are on their way.
医生正往这儿赶来
Gideon,he may be headed your way.
Gideon 他可能朝你们这儿过来了
You know what the odds are of catching a motorcycle with a car in L.A.?
在洛杉矶 要开着汽车抓一辆摩托车 你知道几率有多大么?
Right now,I'm trying not to think about it.
现在我尽量不考虑这几率
There.
在那儿
Damn it.Go.
该死! 我们走!
It's the first time he's made so many mistakes.
他犯了那么多错误 这还是第一次
Hit the bank in the morning,
早上来到银行
more people around.
周围人越来越多
Didn't clear the back room,
没有清空后勤办公室
parked his bike right out front.
把车停在正门口
Didn't bother taking any money.
也没花大力气抢钱
Did almost everything you predicted.
你预计的事儿他几乎都做了
Sometimes it sucks to be right.
有时候 完全正确却糟透了
Witnesses said he refused to take off his clothes.
目击者说他拒绝脱衣服
Damn.
该死
That's enough.
够了
It's not the kind of rage you bottle back up.
这已经不是 胸中所压抑的怒火了
This could be the beginning of a spree.
很可能是 没有节制的放纵行为的开始
How's jj doing on that suspect list?
嫌疑犯清单 JJ处理得怎样了?
I'll call her.
我打她电话
I'll call reid and elle and get them on it,too.
我打给Reid和Elle 叫他们也一起去处理
You don't think he's going to rob another bank?
你认为他不会 再抢另一家银行了吧?
No.
不会了
He doesn't care about money anymore.
他对钱再也没兴趣了
Whatever he's after,
无论他追求的是什么
he'll hurt anyone who gets in his way.
对于妨碍他的人 都决不留情
Hey.
嘿
You call elle and reid?
你打给Elle和Reid了?
Yeah.
对
What's that?
那是什么?
My son's first steps.
儿子第一次走路的情景
I was out of town and haley sent me the file.
我当时在城外 Haley就把文件传了过来
It's nice.
很不错
It's 5 months ago.
这已是五个月前的了
I haven't loaded anything on here since.
那以后 我再也没往手机上 传过什么了
Ok.So you film a new one when you get home.
噢 那你等回到家再录个新的吧
So,you're sure this is it?
你确定就是这样了么?
Yeah. Based on all the parameters,
是的 根据以下所有参数
age,armed robbery charge,
年龄 受过持枪抢劫指控
time spent in prison,
在狱中的时间
approximate location of home address based on geographical profile.
以及根据地理学绘图 得出的大致住址
It's about 360 names
总共约有360个嫌疑人
these guys aren't sweethearts,
这些可不是什么可爱的人
but there's only a handful with sex crimes on their rap sheets
但逮捕记录上记载有性犯罪的 只是少数
and none are sexual sadists.
并且没有性虐待狂
That's not surprising.
并不奇怪
Bank robbers and gun nuts aren't typically sex offenders.
银行劫匪和枪械狂人 都不是典型的性侵犯者
That's what makes this one so unique.
正因这样 这个混蛋才如此与众不同
What about a pimp?
会不会是皮条客?
Roland lynch,32 years old.
Roland Lynch 32岁
Pimps are characteristically sociopath and,
的确 皮条客往往是 典型的反社会者
in many cases,sadistic.
并且在许多情况下 残酷成性
Helps control their employees.
这有助于他们控制手下的人
Well,this one started out robbing convenience stores
此人从抢劫便利店开始
before working his way into pimping.
之后成了皮条客
That's unusual.
倒是不寻常
Pimps typically violate by proxy,
皮条客通常只是中间人
forcing others to do the work for them,whereas,
强迫他人为自己做事 尽管如此
bank robbers usually operate in pairs or alone.
银行劫匪往往两人配合或单独行动
So,he's sexually sadistic and has experience with armed robbery.
那么 他是个性虐待狂 并且曾进行持械抢劫
Along with fitting all other parameters of the profile.
而且他符合我们分析的所有参数
All right.I'll get in touch with his parole officer.
好的 我会和他的假释官联系
You're lynch's parole officer.
你是Lynch的假释官
When was the last time you talked to him?
上一次你和他谈话是什么时候?
Haven't talked to lynch in a month.
一个月没跟Lynch谈话了
What can you tell us about him?
关于Lynch 你能告诉我们些什么?
Roland?
你说Roland?
A real peach.
他可真是"人见人爱"
He used to punish his girls by raping them in front of their little sisters.
他常常为了要惩罚手下的姑娘们 就当着她们的姐妹 强奸她们
He got a habit?
他已经成习惯了?
Which one of mine doesn't?
我监督的哪个人不是这样?
If I'm not mistaken,
如果我没搞错
he probably has about a 10 rock a day monkey.
他可能是个 一天要吸上10次可卡因的吸毒佬
If lynch is our guy,
如果Lynch就是我们要找的人
he's going downhill fast,
他正每况愈下 并且速度惊人
but if he's tweaked,he's going down even faster.
一旦他毒瘾发作 情况就坏得更快
His latest drug test isn't back yet,
他最近一次的药检结果还没有出来
but I'm betting it isn't going to be clean.
但我打赌他肯定不干净
You got a line on him?
你有他的消息么?
Give me a break.You know what my case load is like?
饶了我吧 你知道我的案子负担有多重么?
Hey,come on,maN.
别这样 伙计
He might have beaten a civilian to death with a mac-10,
他可能会用Mac-10冲锋枪 把一个人活活打死
caved in a meter maid's face,and that's just the beginning.
他还袭击了管理车辆的女警 而那仅仅是开始
That make the top of your list?
这足够让你先放下其他事情了吧?
I'll make some calls.
好吧 我去打几个电话
F.B.I. I need roland lynch.
FBI! 我要找Roland Lynch
I need to talk to roland lynch.
我要和他谈谈
Roland lynch?
Roland Lynch?
Hey! Roland lynch?
嘿! Roland Lynch?
Don't even think about it.
想都别想!
Don't move!
别动!
Give it to me.
给我!
Roland,I can count about 16 different ways you've just violated your parole.
Roland 我至少能说出你16条 触犯假释规定的行为
They send in feds for busting parole?
他们让FBI的人来管我 触犯假释规定?
We're here for the bank robberies and the delivery man you killed.
我们是为银行劫案和 被你杀的送货人来的
I don't rob banks.
我才不抢劫银行
You violated parole,
你违反了假释条例
we've got you on possession,
我们要传讯你
you're going down.
你完了
You think I'm gonna roll over 'cause you're waving 3 to 5 at me?
你觉得就凭你们三五个人 我就会垮掉
I took beating's that lasted longer than that.
我能忍受比这个更长的殴打
If i were you,I wouldn't even worry about the murder charge.
如果我是你 我根本不会担心谋杀起诉
I'd worry what happens to you when word gets around you're a pervert.
我会担心当别人听说你是个变态时 你会怎么样
Yeah,well,I made my living being a pervert.
是啊 我靠做性变态者为生
You can tell them that.
你可以这么说
Oh,this is different.
哦 这不同
Went after little old ladies,kids.
调戏老太太 孩子
Witnesses say you got off when the old lady took her shirt off.
目击证人说当老太太脱掉衣服时 你逃走了
Old ladies,kids,inside,think about it.
老太太 孩子 老实说 想想吧
Hey,roland,
嘿 Roland
you're high out of your mind right now,aren't ya?
你现在有些兴奋过头了 是吗?
Get him in the car.
带他上车
Take him back to the field office,
把他带回警察总局
spend a few hours with him,he'll sober up.
跟他耗上几小时 他会清醒的
Give me a pot of coffee and I'll go all night with this fool.
给我来壶咖啡 我就去跟这个家伙待上一晚
Get him out of here.
带他出去
Hey,morgan.
嘿 Morgan
We got him.
我们抓到他了
This guy's a hardcore prison rat.
这个家伙是监狱常客
Hey.
嘿
Hang on.
等等
We just got another call,restaurant in the south bay.
我们刚刚接到又一个电话 在南部海湾的一家饭店
Guy came in in a ski-mask,started making people undress.
一个戴着滑雪面罩的男人闯进来 叫人们都脱衣服
He just shot a 14-year-old kid.
他刚刚射杀了一个14岁的孩子
When?
什么时候?
10 minutes ago.
10 分钟前
What'd she say?
她说了什么?
Hardcore or not,you've got the wrong scumbag.
不管中不中听 你们抓错人了
According to witnesses,
据目击证人说
he came in and fired at the ceiling.
他进来朝天花板开了几枪
Then he separated all the kids from their parents.
他把所有的孩子都和父母分开
Then?
然后呢?
He's forcing the sons to hit their mothers.
他逼迫儿子打他们的母亲
He started to.
一开始是
When he tried to get the first one to hit his mother harder,
当他要让第一个孩子打得更重时
he refused,
他拒绝了
and when he refused...
而他当他拒绝之后...
it doesn't make sense.They're children.
这没道理 他们是孩子
He's playing out a fantasy.
他在演出他的幻想世界
Yeah,but it's his fantasy and someone else's children.
但这是他自己的幻想 但那是别人的孩子
They're surrogates of some kind.
他们是别的东西的替代品
No. You don't do this to someone else's kids to get off.
不 他不会对别人的孩子这么做 以此来发泄
You just don't do it.
他不会这么做
It just doesn't make sense to me.
我不懂
You internalize violence.
要是你把暴力藏在心里
You take it out on other people.
你要对别人发泄愤怒
Why force somebody else to do it?
为什么逼迫别人去做?
Why force children to act out your rage?
为什么让孩子展露自己的愤怒?
He didn't make the children do anything at the bank.
他在银行里没有让孩子们做什么
Manager said he put the parents together.
经理说他把父母放在一起
So,why is he so focused on the kids now?
那么他为什么 现在又专注于孩子们呢?
I want to talk to the bank manager again.
我想再跟银行经理谈谈
I don't know what else I can tell you.
我不知道还能告诉你们什么
I've already gone over it 3 times.
我已经说了3遍了
What we need to know is
我们想知道的是
if there's something in that tape that you don't want us to know about?
录影带里有什么是 你不想让我们知道的吗?
There were 12 other people in that bank who were forced to watch.
当时在银行里还有12个人 被逼着看观看
What could I possibly be hiding?
我有什么可隐藏的?
This is about your children,isn't it?
这关于你的孩子们 是不是?
We're sorry.
我们很遗憾
Mr. Henderson,this is very important.
Henderson先生 这很重要
He's already killed 2 people and he's not going to stop.
他已经杀了2个人了 而且还不准备停手
God! Go ahead.
上帝啊! 说吧
Why don't you tell them what he did to us,
你为什么不告诉他们 他对我们做了什么
what you let him do?
你让他干了什么?
He had a gun.
他有枪
He was going to kill me.
他要杀了我
Come on.
走吧
They took my family from me.
他们夺走了我的家庭
We can't even look at each other anymore.
我们甚至无法再直视彼此
I don't know how a family gets over something like that.
我不知道一个家庭要 怎么才能经受那些
They don'T.
他们不会
Excuse me.
打扰一下
Is it true he would have killed my father if he tried to stand up to him?
如果我父亲反抗 他真的会杀了他吗?
There's no way to know,darren,
这我们无从得知 Darren
but your father did the right thing.
但你父亲做的是对的
Is there some reason you doubt that?
你为什么会怀疑?
It's just...
只是...
the robber said something afterwards.
劫匪后来说了些话
He said he was sorry.
他说他很抱歉
He apologized.
他道歉了
Sadists don't apologize.
施虐狂不会道歉的
They gloat,maybe,
他们可能在幸灾乐祸
but they don't apologize.
但他们是不会道歉的
Our guy's not a sadist.
我们要找的这个人不是施虐狂
We got that part of the profile wrong.
我们有点判断失误了
He doesn't derive any sadistic pleasure from these fantasies,
他并没有从这些幻想中 得到任何施虐的快感
they're--they're more like a compulsion.
他们-- 他们更像是强迫症
Compulsion that's literally life or death?
强迫于简单的生死抉择?
I mean,if anyone interferes,he kills them.
我是说 有人干涉 他就会杀了他们
It's like he's compelled to direct these fantasies using these people as actors.
就像他强迫这些人作为演员
Actors on a stage,it's a play.
舞台上的演员 这是出戏
It's a psychodrama.
是出心理剧
What's that?
那是什么?
It's a form of psychotherapy whereby actors serve as surrogates for actual people in the patient's life.
是一种由演员来扮演病人 生活中真实的人心理疗法
Incorporates many elements of theatre,including an audience.
包含很多戏剧元素 包括观众
There's a very famous pilot program
在90年代中期San Luis的 Obispo县监狱
at the san luis obispo county jail in the mid-nineties.
曾有过一个非常著名的试行计划
Isn't that just a couple hours away from here?
距这里不就几小时车程吗?
Let's go over the suspect list and
让我们再查查嫌疑人名单
see how many of them did time in san luis obispo.
看看有多少人在San Luis的Obispo待过
The answer is 4.
有四个
Come on. Tell me you narrowed it down a little more than that.
拜托 告诉我你还能再把范围缩小点
Only 2 live in state,
只有两个住在本地
but only 1 lives in L.A.
但只有一个住在洛杉矶
Ha,that a girL.
哈 好姑娘
Caleb dale sheppard,last known address 236 harbor lane,inglewood.
Caleb dale sheppard 最后的地址是 Habor街236号 Inglewood
Thanks,mama.
谢谢 女士
That's only 1.6 miles from the last restaurant he hit.
距上一个他袭击的餐馆 只有1.6 英里
I've been studying a lot of L.A. Maps.
我研究过很多洛杉矶的地图
If he's been attacking that close to home,
如果他在家附近袭击
he's given up any interest in protecting his identity.
他就不再对隐藏身份感兴趣了
You all go down there and split up,half to his address,
你们都过去 一半人去他那个地址
half patrol around the restaurant in case he's on the hunt.
另一半人到餐馆附近巡逻 以防他开始行动
Mrs. Sheppard,do you know where your son is?
Sheppard太太 你知道你儿子在哪里吗?
Dale doesn't live here anymore.
Dale不住这已经很久了
Where is he,mrs. Sheppard?
他在哪里 Sheppard太太?
He's a grown man.
他是个成年人
You have any idea how much trouble your son could be in?
你知道你儿子身陷于多少麻烦中吗?
Jail?
监狱?
He's a good boy.
他是个好孩子
Lost his way a bit,that's all.
有点迷途 但仅此而已
Well,that's one way to look at 12 years in and out of prison.
哦 另一种看待12年进出监狱的方法
You've never made a mistake?
难道你从没犯过错吗?
Your son spent time in a juvenile home?
您的儿子在青少年之家待过吗?
He was out of control,
他失去控制了
even attacked his own sister once,
甚至有一次袭击了自己的妹妹
but his father died.
但他父亲死了
It wasn't his fault.
那不是他的错
Was it yours?
是你的错吗?
What?
什么?
Was it your fault?
是不是你的错?
How many of these did you take today,mrs. Sheppard?
你今天吃了多少这个药 Sheppard太太?
I had back problems my whole life.
我的背一直有问题
She's completely out of her mind.
她疯了
She's so lonely she'll just keep talking to us.
她太孤单了 才要一直跟我们讲话
I doubt she'll tell us where he is.
我怀疑她会不会 告诉我们他在哪里
That was garcia.
是Garcia的电话
Apparently sheppard's sister died 12 years ago,suicide.
很显然Sheppard的妹妹 12年前死了 是自杀的
Lady sure did a number on her kids.
这位女士肯定没好好教导孩子
She's probably lonely after the husband died and on painkillers,
在丈夫死后她一直很孤独 并依赖止痛药
not in her right mind,
甚至还有点神志不清
nobody there to turn to but sheppard and his sister.
处了Sheppard和他妹妹 没人可以依赖
So,now he's symbolically punishing his mother?
所以现在他象征性的 惩罚他的母亲?
He's playing out a fantasy.
他在演出幻想
Sons gaining total control over their mothers.
儿子要完全掌控母亲
We got something.
我们找到了些东西
"Dale daybreak hotel."
"Dale日出旅馆"
Sheppard,F.B.I.
Sheppard 联邦调查局
Key?
钥匙?
No,I got one.
不 我有办法
Clear!
没人!
Yeah,it's clear here,too.
是啊 这里也没人
Morgan.
Morgan
Crystal meth.
(甲安菲他明)冰毒
Oh,he's got to be halfway out of his mind by now.
现在他很快就要神志不清了
Which would explain why he left this behind.
这也就解释了 他为什么会把这个留下来
Well,it looks like he's on foot.Here's his bike.
看上去他好像是徒步的 这是他的摩托车
I'm calling hotch.
我打给Hotch
Yeah?
怎么?
Look,he's not here.
看上去他不在这里
From the looks of it,he just left.
从这里的情况看来 他刚刚离开
Hotch,he's tweakin'.
Hotch 他发作了
He's unmasked and he's probably on foot.
他没戴面具 可能步行
All right,stay there.Call if there's any sign of him.
好的 呆在那 有任何他的消息就打电话过来
Ok. You. Too.
好的 你也一样
If he's on foot,he must still be in the neighborhood.
如果他是步行的 他一定还在附近
How do we find him?
我们要怎么找到他?
At this point,he'll probably hit the first thing that catches his attention.
现在他很可能会袭击 第一个引起他注意的东西
Families.
家庭
Public places.
公共场所
If the trend continues,he'll look for a bigger audience.
如果这种趋势继续延续 他会寻找更多观众
Public place with families.
有很多家庭的公共场所
Guys,there's a public park not far from here.
伙计们 距这里不远有一个公园
Where?
哪里?
.6 miles from where we are now.
距这里0.6英里
.9 miles from the hotel where the unsub's staying,
距离嫌犯居住的旅馆0.9英里
which we'll actually pass if we take a right at the next light.
如果我们在下个交通灯那里右转 就会经过
It doesn't matter what they say
* It doesn't matter what they say *
in the jealous games people play,hey ey ey
* in the jealous games people play, hey ey ey *
There's no sign of him.
没有看见他
We've got cruisers everywhere.Where could he be?
我们到处都有人巡逻 他可能在哪里?
There's only a few blocks betweenhere and his hotel.
这里距他的旅馆只有几个街区
He's got to be really close.
他一定就在附近
-Do it. -No.
- 快做 - 不
I said,do it.
我说了 快做!
No.
不
Do it.It's ok.
- 快开枪 - 没事的
Come on,you can do it.
快点 你能做到的
No,no.
不 不
Please,just do what he says,please.
求你了 快点照他说的做
I said do it!
我说了 快开枪!
Please,do what he says.
求你了 照他说的做
It's ok,sweethearT.
没事的 甜心
Mommy says it's ok.
妈妈说了没事的
Put it down.
把刀放下
Drop the knife.
快把刀放下
It won't fix you,sheppard.
这不会治好你的 Sheppard
It doesn't matter what you make them do,
无论你让他们做什么
how many people are watching you.
不管有多少人看着你
Oh,my god.
哦 我的上帝啊
Got him.
抓到他了
It's ok.
没事的
Look at these people.
看看这些人
Look at them!
看着他们!
They're children.
他们是孩子
for god's sake.
看在上帝份上
I need something that kills.
我需要止痛药
Give me something.
给我点药
I need something. Aah!
我需要点东西! 啊!
You shot me!
你开枪射我!
You had a hunting knife to a little boy's throat.
你把猎刀架在小男孩的脖子上
Just give me something for the pain,
给我点止痛的药
you son of a bitch!
你这个狗娘养的!
She did it!
是她干的!
Who did?
谁干的?
My mama.
我妈妈
You don't know what she did to me.
你不知道她对我干了什么
Did you really think you were going to get back at your mom
你真的觉得你能通过袭击别人
by attacking all these other people?
让你母亲受到报应吗?
The bitch deserved it.
那个婊子活该
Except you didn't go after her,
你不去针对她
you went after all these other women.
你就针对别的女人
So what?
又怎么样?
You went after children.
你针对孩子们
They're going to have to learn sooner or later.
他们会迟早明白的
What are they going to have to learn?
他们要明白什么?
That no one's there for you.
没有人关心你
He's a drug addict.He's detoxing.
他是个吸毒者 他发作了
I don't care what he asks for.
我不管他要什么
Don't give him anything.
什么都别给他
Come on.
拜托
He's not a doctor.
他又不是医生
He's right.I'm an F.B.I. Agent,and he killed a 14-year-old boy today.
他说的没错 我是联邦调查局特工 他今天杀害了一个14岁的孩子
"The basis of shame is not some personal mistake of ours,
"羞耻的本质并不是我们个人的错误
but that this humiliation is seen by everyone."
而是被他人看见的耻辱"
Milan kundera.
米兰昆德拉
You ok?
你还好吧?
I was showing those trainees around the offices the other day.
我有天在带领培训人员 参观办公室
They all want to be in the bau.
他们都想到行为分析局工作
I told them what a great job it is.
我告诉他们这是多么伟大的工作
And they even applauded when the tour was over.
参观结束后他们都一起鼓掌
I heard.
我听见了
Yeah,but I really didn't tell them the truth.
但我并没有告诉他们事实
I didn't tell them what it's like to spend your days in this hell.
我没有告诉他们 在这个地狱工作是什么感觉
It's fun,huh?
很有趣 嗯?
I mean,who's to blame for somebody like sheppard?
我是说 像sheppard这样的人 能去怪谁呢?
His mother?
他母亲?
Broken home?
破碎的家庭?
Society?
社会?
All of it?
全都要怪?
None of it?
一个也不能责怪?
It gets worse and worse with each case.
每办一个案子就变得更糟
Save one life,we save the world.
救人一命 就能救全世界
Yeah.
是啊
Well,the one thing I didn't tell the trainees.
还有一件事 我没有告诉受训人员
What's that?
什么?
We do not get paid enough.
我们薪水太低
You got that right.
你说对了